hireme@natan.la https://natan.la github.com/natanlao linkedin.com/in/natanlao

Hi. I'm a wannabe software engineer in my second year of studying computer engineering at UC Santa Cruz. I have a good 5+ years experience with Python and I'm a fast learner.

Experience

Research assistant Nov 2016 - Present

UCSC Genomics Institute

Worked on Toil, a pure-Python workflow engine used for big biomedical data analysis. I helped develop Toil's interfaces to the commercial cloud (Azure, EC2, etc.).

Python AWS Azure Docker Ansible

Software engineering intern Summer 2015

Hewlett-Packard, Inc.

Networking R&D Lab. Built web app to monitor, locate, and configure R&D hardware. Helped automate config and deployment of test devices.

Flask HTML CSS Javascript

Technical intern Summer 2017

Hewlett-Packard Enterprise

Developed secure, scalable interface PoC to streamline analysis and distribution of business operations data for Network R&D Operations team.

Microsoft SQL Server VBA

Student technician Jul 2014 - Aug 2016

Roseville Joint Union HSD

Provided end-user support to over 2000 students, faculty, and staff. Simultaneously worked as a stage technician, managing and maintaining theater lighting and sound systems.

Education

UC Santa Cruz 2016 - 2020 (Projected) B.S. Computer Engineering, minor in CS. College Scholars program member.

Java C Algorithms Data structures

Woodcreek High School 2012 - 2016 Graduated 2016 with 4.28 GPA. Ranked 12 of 438 in my class. National AP Scholar.

Spanish (biliterate) Public speaking

Selected achievements and service

Runner-up, HACK UCSC 2017

Led team of five developing a student-to-student textbook swap app in Python. Runner-up out of 42 other teams.

Head student instructor 2017 - Present

Head TA for UCSC's largest student-led class, teaching basics of debate and politics to 90+ students quarterly. Oversee team of 10-15 TAs.

VP, National Honor Society 2016

Led 150+ students as VP. Raised \$10K+ for community nonprofits and used automation to streamline administration.

2nd Place, HPE Best in Class 2017

Placed second out of over 40 interns at Hewlett-Packard Enterprise in competition showcasing summer internship projects.